AI conversations quickly become a second workspace. After months of use,
active projects are mixed with old versions, repeated decisions, forgotten
tasks, and unrelated questions. ChatGPT Project Organizer turns exported
conversations into structured, evidence-backed, and reversible projects.
The workflow starts by importing JSON, CSV, or TXT. Source files are copied
into protected storage, hashed, normalized, and never edited. The included
anonymized demo contains thirty-three conversations and fifty-one messages.
Before using a language model, deterministic rules identify objective signals:
exact and partial duplicates, version precedence, approved or rejected decisions,
pending tasks, and explicit project states. Every finding keeps the exact
conversation evidence that supports it.
GPT-5.6 then reconstructs semantic project context through the OpenAI Responses
API and a strict Pydantic Structured Output. It identifies seven projects,
current and discarded versions, decisions, tasks, blockers, memberships,
and ambiguous cases. The reproducible demo is clearly labelled as precomputed.
Live mode uses GPT-5.6 when an API key is configured.
The application generates one global proposal instead of asking the user
to organize every chat. Sixteen safe operations can be approved as a batch.
Only four exceptions require correction or rejection, so human attention
is focused where it matters.
A mandatory before-and-after preview shows exactly what will change. Applying
the proposal updates only a simulated derived workspace. The original conversations
remain untouched, and every authorized operation is written to an ordered
audit history.
Undo restores the exact previous workspace hash while preserving audit history.
Codex accelerated the architecture, React and FastAPI implementation, tests,
debugging, release validation, and documentation. Human decisions defined
immutable originals, evidence precedence, approval gates, and the reversible
workflow.
The result is a working prototype where AI performs the heavy analysis without
removing user control. It organizes knowledge, explains its decisions, protects
the source, and makes every operation reversible.